IBE KINGSLEY NDUKA

+2348069364217, +2347036294685| ibenoahs@gmail.com | 46Demureen Street, Ketu-Alapere, Lagos, Nigeria...

SUMMARY

Efficient and reliable Software Developer with proven experience in web applications, desktop applications development, client side, server side programming. Basic Javascript, Node JS, Express, plethora of database management platform such as SQL, NoSQL. Resourceful problem-solver who constantly seeks effectiveness to ensure favorable outcomes for organizations worked for and their clients. Good team player and individual contributor with comprehensive knowledge in providing desktop and web applications development, monitoring and updating of Front-End Designs, debugging and modifying different software components, and general software development.

EXPERIENCE

TH.O, London, England – JUNIOR BLOCKCHAIIN DEVEOPER INTERN JUNE 2021

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Creating of token, private and public chains
- Writing of smart contracts
- Connecting smart contracts with frontend
- Connecting smart contracts with backend
- Working with Dragon chain blockchain
- Frontend development
- Assisting Senior developers
- Meeting with the development team to discuss user interface ideas and application

Ace Africa Software, Lagos, Nigeria – INTERN FULLSTACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Nov 2019 – May 2021

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Designed and developed computer software web applications, desktop and mobile applications
- Project Manager for Royal Ministries Website Development Designed and managed the company's Database
 Maintained existing applications, designed and delivered new applications.
- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance software development.
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.
- Conceived, designed and wrote highly maintainable, solid code in Node JS, JavaScript, python for software that formed core framework and has won consistent praise from subsequent developers since initial version.

 © Constantly monitored and managed Database with the aid of SQL, MongoDB.

Sabaton Services, Lagos Nigeria - WEB DEVELOPER & IT SUPPORT (REMOTE) Sept 2019 - July 2020

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Designed and developed highly responsive web application packages that are compatible with top browsers such as Firefox, Chrome and Safari etc.
- Re-designed and developed company's website using Node JS, JavaScript, Template Engine and CSS.

 Designed and managed the company's Database
- IT consultant

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Trained Young Adults on web design with word press and basic front-end designs

 Crating new pages and contents using Word Press and Elementor Pro plugin.
- Managing and updating company's web contents
- IT consultant

Sysmax Technologies, Benue Nigeria – WEB DESIGNER Mar 2018 – Oct 2018

JOB DESCRIPTION:

- Web designing with Word Press and Elementor
- Maintaining and updating company's website
- · Maintaining and updating clients websites
- Data Entry

SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

- Operations Administration and Team Management
- Exceptional time management
- Innovative
- User requirements
- Programming documentation
- Basic JavaScript
- Web design Wordpress
- CSS/HTML
- Advanced problem solving skill

- Back-End Proficiency with Node JS
- Negotiation & Conflict Resolution
- Creativity
- Complex problem-solving
- People management
- Effective Communication (Oral and Writing)
 Microsoft Office Suites Word, Excel.

EDUCATION

BSC. Computer Science - Open University Of Nigeria, Nigeria.

Oct 2020

Saviour College Schools

Senior School Certificate. 2011 -2017

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

